http://www.fischer-technology.com/privacy

Jump to the content of the pageMeasurements (Show submenu)Coating Thickness MeasurementMaterial AnalysisAutomationNanoindentationScratch Test MeasurementsElectrical ConductivityFerrite ContentSurface ProfilePorosity Testing MethodSalt ContaminationDew PointIndustries (Show submenu)Material Analysis & Measurement Technology in Aeronautics, Aerospace (Show submenu)Aerospace Coating Mechanical Properties TestingHigh Reliability Measurement TechnologyAutomotive Measurement Technology (Show submenu)Measuring Lacquer Layers in Automotive IndustryCDP and ZN Coating MeasurementMeasuring Hard Coatings, PVD, CVD, DLC and NiPMeasure Sprayable Acoustic Coatings (SAM)Construction and Infrastructure (Show submenu)SSPC-PA2Steel RoofingMeasurement Technology for Electronics and Semiconductor Industry (Show submenu)Quality Assurance in PCB ManufacturingWafer and SemiconductorsRoHs, WEEE, EOLV or CPSIA For Electronic ComponentsMeasurement Technology For Electronic ComponentsMeasure Coatings on Lead FramesEngineering Materials (Show submenu)Machining and Milling ToolsFasteners (Show submenu)Zinc LayersStainless Steel AlloysFood and Beverages (Show submenu)Measure Protective Coatings in Packaging IndustryGold, Watches and Jewelry (Show submenu)Quality Control of High End WatchesAlloy Analysis of Precious MetalsMaterial Analysis of Fashion Jewelry and AccessoriesHousehold Fixtures and Accessories (Show submenu)Cr/Ni/Cu/ABSIron and Steel (Show submenu)Hot-Dip GalvanizationThermal Sprayed CoatingsMarine and Transportation Technology (Show submenu)Measuring Anti Corrosion CoatingsMedical and Pharmaceutical (Show submenu)Enamel CoatingsMedical ImplantsMedical DevicesDental CompositesOil, Gas and Petrochemicals (Show submenu)Measurement Technology for PipelinesSteel and Weld SeamsCoating Meausrement for Storage TanksOptics and Fine Mechanics (Show submenu)Lenses and Optical ComponentsLCDsPaint & Varnish Coating Instruments (Show submenu)Paint Coating Thickness MeasurementsPlating Services (Show submenu)Plating ApplicationsAutomationBath AnalysisAluminium and AnodizationCoatings in Power Generation and Energy (Show submenu)Solar Module Coating Testing & AnalysisCladdingsHeat Recovery BoilersComposition Measurement of Recycling (Show submenu)Catalytic ConvertersSpecial Solutions (Show submenu)Mechanical PropertiesTextiles (Show submenu)Harmful SubstancesTesting Labs (Show submenu)Heavy Metal DetectionArcheologyProducts (Show submenu)X-RAY XRFHandheld GaugesAutomationCOULOSCOPE and MMS Benchtop InstrumentsNanoindentation and Scratch TestingOpticsTechnologies (Show submenu)XRF - Energy dispersive X-ray fluorescence analysisMagnetic InductionEddy Current Test MethodPhase-Sensitive Eddy CurrentDuplex Coating MeasurementMagnetic MethodMicroresistivityCoulometryInstrumented Indentation - NanoindentationScratch Test MethodSurface ProfileBresle Test Salt KitDew Point MeasurementHoliday Test MethodMeasuring Ferrite ContentElectrical Conductivity TestingServices (Show submenu)Application LabsSeminars and TrainingCustomer ServiceCertifications and AccreditionsCertified Calibration Standards for Measurement TechnologyStatisticsCommon Questions about Measurement Technology (Show submenu)FAQ X-RAY XRFFAQ Coating Thickness GagesFAQ Duplex MeasurementsFAQ SIGMASCOPEFAQ CalibrationFAQ Coulometric Measuring MethodFAQ NanoindentationFAQ Scratch TestHelmut Fischer Download CenterCompany (Show submenu)About Helmut FischerCareers at Helmut Fischer (Show submenu)Job OpportunitiesFischer as an EmployerProfessionals and GraduatesUniversity Students and High School StudentsWhat's new in Industrial Measurement TechnologyMeasurement Technology Events (Show submenu)Trade Shows and ConferencesSeminarsWebinarsContact (Show submenu)BrazilChinaFranceGermanyHong-KongIndiaItalyJapanMalaysiaMexicoNetherlandsSingaporeSouth KoreaSpainSwitzerlandTaiwanThailandUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited States of AmericaVietnamAll other Countries: Our Partners WorldwideStatement about CoronavirusFischer Blog (Show submenu)Fischer is on Board: "Christmas in a Shoe Box"Open House on the First Fischer Application DayFor faster and more precise measurements: the new DPP+X-Ray Fluorescence Analysis (Part 2)MMS PC2 in a production facilityDr. Bernd Binder presenting FISCHERSCOPE ST200X-RAY XDLM TutorialsMeasurement of Electroplated Coatings on Gravure CylindersGreenwood Fabricating & Plating Success StoryPut your trust in AutomationIntroducing the MMS Inspection SeriesFERITSCOPE FMP Tutorials3DDC Success StoryFischer Technology Inc. Celebrates its 40th AnniversaryFischer MMS Inspection TutorialMeasurement of Cr/Ni/Cu coatings of a shower headHelmut Fischer Announces Grand Opening of New Assembly Plant in IndiaX-Ray Fluorescence Analysis (Part 1)X-RAY XDV-µ TutorialsCoatings on Electrical Contacts: Using the X-ray Fluorescence MethodXAN 500 TutorialsCalibration of Coating Thickness InstrumentsXAN 500 – Flexible XRF Measurement TechnologyAutomated Measurement SolutionsCircuit Boards – Printed ProgressSolutions for Coating Thickness measurement: MP0/MP0R SeriesWatch Quality Assurance: Swiss Quality WatchesScratch Test: How to Test and Evaluate Results?FISCHERSCOPE® ST200 Scratch Tester Tutorial VideoHelmut Fischer Knowledge SeminarsMobile XRF Measuring Instrument: X-RAY XAN 500Gujarat Gold and Jewellery Show Review 2019 Fischer offers a wide range of solutions for the specific requirements of various industries and sectors. Find the right gauge for your measuring task here: Choose industryChoose industryMaterial Analysis & Measurement Technology in Aeronautics, AerospaceAutomotive Measurement TechnologyConstruction and InfrastructureMeasurement Technology for Electronics and Semiconductor IndustryEngineering MaterialsFastenersFood and BeveragesPrecise Measurements of Gold, Watches, JewelryHousehold Fixtures and AccessoriesIron and SteelMarine And Transportation Measurement TechnologyMedical and PharmaceuticalOil, Gas and PetrochemicalsOptics and Fine MechanicsPaint & Varnish Coating InstrumentsPlating ServicesCoatings in Power Generation and EnergyComposition Measurement of RecyclingSpecial SolutionsTextilesTesting LabsLoading …Choose applicationChoose applicationAerospace Coating Mechanical Properties TestingAlloy Analysis of Precious MetalsAluminium and AnodizationArcheologyAutomationBath AnalysisCatalytic ConvertersCDP and ZN Coating MeasurementCladdingsCoating Meausrement for Storage TanksCr/Ni/Cu/ABSDental CompositesEnamel CoatingsHarmful SubstancesHeat Recovery BoilersHeavy Metal DetectionHigh Reliability Measurement TechnologyHot-Dip GalvanizationLCDsLenses and Optical ComponentsMachining and Milling ToolsMaterial Analysis of Fashion Jewelry and AccessoriesMeasure Coatings on Lead FramesMeasure Protective Coatings in Packaging IndustryMeasure Sprayable Acoustic Coatings (SAM)Measurement Technology For Electronic ComponentsMeasurement Technology for PipelinesMeasuring Anti Corrosion CoatingsMeasuring Hard Coatings, PVD, CVD, DLC and NiPMeasuring Lacquer Layers in Automotive IndustryMechanical PropertiesMedical DevicesMedical ImplantsPaint Coating Thickness MeasurementsPlating ApplicationsQuality Assurance in PCB ManufacturingQuality Control of High End WatchesRoHs, WEEE, EOLV or CPSIA For Electronic ComponentsSolar Module Coating Testing & AnalysisSSPC-PA2Stainless Steel AlloysSteel and Weld SeamsSteel RoofingThermal Sprayed CoatingsWafer and SemiconductorsZinc LayersLoading …Submit Search product name Product searchEnter the desired product or series name and get directly to the product through the suggested results. Show all products SearchFischer Worldwide:Change locationEgyptSyriaAlgeriaChinaSouth KoreaJapanThailandTaiwanIndiaHong Kong SAR of ChinaSingaporeMalaysiaUnited Arab EmiratesVietnamOmanBahrainBangladeshGermanyFranceItalySpainUnited KingdomSwitzerlandNetherlandsTurkeyUnited StatesMexicoBrazilAll Others …Select language:EnglishGermanChinese (traditional)DutchItalianJapaneseKoreanSpanishTurkishShow/hide the menuMeasurementsIndustriesProductsTechnologiesServicesCompanyFischer BlogHomeHelmut Fischer Privacy PolicyHelmut Fischer Privacy Policy
Cookie settings
Under the following links you can adjust your cookie settings: Change Settings
Reset
General information The following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview of what will happen with your personal data when you visit our website. The term „personal data“ comprises all data that can be used to personally identify you. For detailed information about the subject matter of data protection, please consult our Data Protection Declaration, which we have included beneath this copy. Data recording on our website Who is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e. the „controller“)?
The data on this website is processed by the operator of the website, whose contact information is available under section „Information Required by Law“ on this website.
How do we record your data?
We collect your data as a result of your sharing of your data with us. This may, for instance be information you enter into our contact form.
Our IT systems automatically record other data when you visit our website. This data comprises primarily technical information (e.g. web browser, operating system or time the site was accessed). This information is recorded automatically when you access our website.
What are the purposes we use your data for?
A portion of the information is generated to guarantee the error free provision of the website. Other data may be used to analyse your user patterns.
What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?
You have the right to receive information about the source, recipients and purposes of your archived personal data at any time without having to pay a fee for such disclosures. You also have the right to demand that your data are rectified, blocked or eradicated. Please do not hesitate to contact us at any time under the address disclosed in section „Information Required by Law“ on this website if you have questions about this or any other data protection related issues. You also have the right to log a complaint with the competent supervising agency.
Moreover, under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data. For details, please consult the Data Protection Declaration under section „Right to Restriction of Data Processing.“ Analysis tools and tools provided by third parties There is a possibility that your browsing patterns will be statistically analysed when your visit our website. Such analyses are performed primarily with cookies and with what we refer to as analysis programmes. As a rule, the analyses of your browsing patterns are conducted anonymously; i.e. the browsing patterns cannot be traced back to you.
You have the option to object to such analyses or you can prevent their performance by not using certain tools. For detailed information about the tools and about your options to object, please consult our Data Protection Declaration below.
Data protection The operators of this website and its pages take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Hence, we handle your personal data as confidential information and in compliance with the statutory data protection regulations and this Data Protection Declaration.
Whenever you use this website, a variety of personal information will be collected. Personal data comprises data that can be used to personally identify you. This Data Protection Declaration explains which data we collect as well as the purposes we use this data for. It also explains how, and for which purpose the information is collected.
We herewith advise you that the transmission of data via the Internet (i.e. through e-mail communications) may be prone to security gaps. It is not possible to completely protect data against third party access. Information about the responsible party (referred to as the „controller“ in the GDPR) The data processing controller on this website is:
HELMUT FISCHER GMBH INSTITUT FÜR ELEKTRONIK UND MESSTECHNIK Industriestraße 21 71069 Sindelfingen Germany
Phone: +49 (0) 70 31 / 3 03 - 0
E-mail: mail@helmut-fischer.de
The controller is the natural person or legal entity that single-handedly or jointly with others makes decisions as to the purposes of and resources for the processing of personal data (e.g. names, e-mail addresses, etc.). Designation of a data protection officer as mandated by law We have appointed a data protection officer for our company.
Christian Schwinge schwinge GmbH Am Kochenhof 12 70192 Stuttgart Germany
Phone: +497112585600 E-mail: christian.schwinge@helmut-fischer.com Revocation of your consent to the processing of data A wide range of data processing transactions are possible only subject to your express consent. You can also revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation. Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR) In the event that data are processed on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. e or f GDPR, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your personal data based on grounds arising from your unique situation. This also applies to any profiling based on these provisions. To determine the legal basis, on which any processing of data is based, please consult this Data Protection Declaration. If you log an objection, we will no longer process your affected personal data, unless we are in a position to present compelling protection worthy grounds for the processing of your data, that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the purpose of the processing is the claiming, exercising or defence of legal entitlements (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR).
If your personal data is being processed in order to engage in direct advertising, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your affected personal data for the purposes of such advertising. This also applies to profiling to the extent that it is affiliated with such direct advertising. If you object, your personal data will subsequently no longer be used for direct advertising purposes (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 2 GDPR). Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agency In the event of violations of the GDPR, data subjects are entitled to log a complaint with a supervisory agency, in particular in the member state where they usually maintain their domicile, place of work or at the place where the alleged violation occurred. The right to log a complaint is in effect regardless of any other administrative or court proceedings available as legal recourses. Right to data portability You have the right to demand that we hand over any data we automatically process on the basis of your consent or in order to fulfil a contract be handed over to you or a third party in a commonly used, machine readable format. If you should demand the direct transfer of the data to another controller, this will be done only if it is technically feasible. SSL and/or TLS encryption For security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content, such as purchase orders or inquiries you submit to us as the website operator, this website uses either an SSL or a TLS encryption programme. You can recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the browser switches from „http://“ to „https://“ and also by the appearance of the lock icon in the browser line.
If the SSL or TLS encryption is activated, data you transmit to us cannot be read by third parties. Encrypted payment transactions on this website If you are under an obligation to share your payment information (e.g. account number if you give us the authority to debit your bank account) with us after you have entered into a fee-based contract with us, this information is required to process payments.
Payment transactions using common modes of paying (Visa/MasterCard, debit to your bank account) are processed exclusively via encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the browser switches from „http://“ to „https://“ and also by the appearance of the lock icon in the browser line.
If the communication with us is encrypted, third parties will not be able to read the payment information you share with us. Information about, blockage, rectification and eradication of data Within the scope of the applicable statutory provisions, you have the right to at any time demand information about your archived personal data, their source and recipients as well as the purpose of the processing of your data. You may also have a right to have your data rectified, blocked or eradicated. If you have questions about this subject matter or any other questions about personal data, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time at the address provided in section „Information Required by Law.“ Right to demand processing restrictions You have the right to demand the imposition of restrictions as far as the processing of your personal data is concerned. To do so, you may contact us at any time at the address provided in section „Information Required by Law.“ The right to demand restriction of processing applies in the following cases: In the event that you should dispute the correctness of your data archived by us, we will usually need some time to verify this claim. During the time that this investigation is ongoing, you have the right to demand that we restrict the processing of your personal data. If the processing of your personal data was/is conducted in an unlawful manner, you have the option to demand the restriction of the processing of your data in lieu of demanding the eradication of this data. If we do not need your personal data any longer and you need it to exercise, defend or claim legal entitlements, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data instead of its eradication. If you have raised an objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR, your rights and our rights will have to be weighed against each other. As long as it has not been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to demand a restriction of the processing of your personal data.If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data – with the exception of their archiving – may be processed only subject to your consent or to claim, exercise or defend legal entitlements or to protect the rights of other natural persons or legal entities or for important public interest reasons cited by the European Union or a member state of the EU. Rejection of unsolicited e-mails We herewith object to the use of contact information published in conjunction with the mandatory information to be provided in section „Information Required by Law“ to send us promotional and information material that we have not expressly requested. The operators of this website and its pages reserve the express right to take legal action in the event of the unsolicited sending of promotional information, for instance via SPAM messages.
Cookies In some instances, our website and its pages use so-called cookies. Cookies do not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain viruses. The purpose of cookies is to make our website more user friendly, effective and more secure. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer and stored by your browser.
Most of the cookies we use are so-called „session cookies.“ They are automatically deleted after your leave our site. Other cookies will remain archived on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to recognise your browser the next time you visit our website.
You can adjust the settings of your browser to make sure that you are notified every time cookies are placed and to enable you to accept cookies only in specific cases or to exclude the acceptance of cookies for specific situations or in general and to activate the automatic deletion of cookies when you close your browser. If you deactivate cookies, the functions of this website may be limited.
Cookies that are required for the performance of the electronic communications transaction or to provide certain functions you want to use (e.g. the shopping cart function), are stored on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in storing cookies to ensure the technically error free and optimised provision of the operator’s services. If other cookies (e.g. cookies for the analysis of your browsing patterns) should be stored, they are addressed separately in this Data Protection Declaration. Server log files The provider of this website and its pages automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser communicates to us automatically. The information comprises: The type and version of browser used The used operating system Referrer URL The hostname of the accessing computer The time of the server inquiry The IP addressThis data is not merged with other data sources.
This data is recorded on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the technically error free depiction and the optimization of the operator’s website. In order to achieve this, server log files must be recorded. Contact form If you submit inquiries to us via our contact form, the information provided in the contact form as well as any contact information provided therein will be stored by us in order to handle your inquiry and in the event that we have further questions. We will not share this information without your consent.
Hence, the processing of the data entered into the contact form occurs exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.
The information you have entered into the contact form shall remain with us until you ask us to eradicate the data, revoke your consent to the archiving of data or if the purpose for which the information is being archived no longer exists (e.g. after we have concluded our response to your inquiry). This shall be without prejudice to any mandatory legal provisions – in particular retention periods. Request by e-mail, telephone or fax If you contact us by e-mail, telephone or fax, your request, including all resulting personal data (name, request) will be stored and processed by us for the purpose of processing your request. We do not pass these data on without your consent.
The processing of these data is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR, if your request is related to the execution of a contract or if it is necessary to carry out pre-contractual measures. In all other cases, the processing is based on your consent (Article 6 (1) a GDPR) and/or on our legitimate interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR), since we have a legitimate interest in the effective processing of requests addressed to us.
The data sent by you to us via contact requests remain with us until you request us to delete, revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage lapses (e.g. after completion of your request). Mandatory statutory provisions - in particular statutory retention periods - remain unaffected. Registration on this website You have the option to register on our website to be able to use additional website functions. We shall use the data you enter only for the purpose of using the respective offer or service you have registered for. The required information we request at the time of registration must be entered in full. Otherwise we shall reject the registration.
To notify you of any important changes to the scope of our portfolio or in the event of technical modifications, we shall use the e-mail address provided during the registration process.
We shall process the data entered during the registration process on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.
The data recorded during the registration process shall be stored by us as long as you are registered on our website. Subsequently, such data shall be deleted. This shall be without prejudice to mandatory statutory retention obligations. Processing of data (customer and contract data) We collect, process and use personal data only to the extent necessary for the establishment, content organization or change of the legal relationship (data inventory). These actions are taken on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR, which permits the processing of data for the fulfilment of a contract or pre-contractual actions. We collect, process and use personal data concerning the use of our website (usage data) only to the extent that this is necessary to make it possible for users to utilize the services and to bill for them.
The collected customer data shall be eradicated upon completion of the order or the termination of the business relationship. This shall be without prejudice to any statutory retention mandates.
Google Analytics This website uses functions of the web analysis service Google Analytics. The provider of this service is Google Ireland Limited („Google“), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.
Google Analytics uses so-called cookies. Cookies are text files, which are stored on your computer and that enable an analysis of the use of the website by users. The information generated by cookies on your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the United States, where it is stored.
The storage of Google Analytics cookies and the utilization of this analysis tool are based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of this website has a legitimate interest in the analysis of user patterns to optimize both, the services offered online and the operator’s advertising activities. By clicking "Confirm selection" or "Select & confirm all", you also provide your consent in accordance with Art. 49 Para. 1 P. 1 lit. a GDPR for your data to be processed by the corresponding services in the USA. The USA is considered by the European Court of Justice to be a country with a level of data protection that is inadequate by EU standards. In particular, there is a risk that your data may be processed by US authorities for control and monitoring purposes, possibly without any possibility of legal recourse. If you click "Accept only required cookies", the transfer described above will not take place.
IP anonymization
On this website, we have activated the IP anonymization function. As a result, your IP address will be abbreviated by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other states that have ratified the Convention on the European Economic Area prior to its transmission to the United States. The full IP address will be transmitted to one of Google’s servers in the United States and abbreviated there only in exceptional cases. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google shall use this information to analyse your use of this website to generate reports on website activities and to render other services to the operator of this website that are related to the use of the website and the Internet. The IP address transmitted in conjunction with Google Analytics from your browser shall not be merged with other data in Google’s possession.
Browser plug-in
You do have the option to prevent the archiving of cookies by making pertinent changes to the settings of your browser software. However, we have to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their fullest extent. Moreover, you have the option prevent the recording of the data generated by the cookie and affiliated with your use of the website (including your IP address) by Google as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link:
https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en.
Objection to the recording of data
You have the option to prevent the recording of your data by Google Analytics by clicking on the following link. This will result in the placement of an opt out cookie, which prevents the recording of your data during future visits to this website:
Google Analytics deactivation.
For more information about the handling of user data by Google Analytics, please consult Google’s Data Privacy Declaration at:
https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en.
Contract data processing
We have executed a contract data processing agreement with Google and are implementing the stringent provisions of the German data protection agencies to the fullest when using Google Analytics.
Archiving period
Data on the user or incident level stored by Google linked to cookies, user IDs or advertising IDs (e.g. DoubleClick cookies, Android advertising ID) will be anonymized or deleted after 26 month. For details please click the following link:
https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?hl=en
Newsletter data If you would like to subscribe to the newsletter offered on this website, we will need from you an e-mail address as well as information that allow us to verify that you are the owner of the e-mail address provided and consent to the receipt of the newsletter. No further data shall be collected or shall be collected only on a voluntary basis. We shall use such data only for the sending of the requested information and shall not share such data with any third parties.
The processing of the information entered into the newsletter subscription form shall occur exclusively on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You may revoke the consent you have given to the archiving of data, the e-mail address and the use of this information for the sending of the newsletter at any time, for instance by clicking on the „Unsubscribe“ link in the newsletter. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data processing transactions that have taken place to date.
The data you archive with us for the purpose of the newsletter subscription shall be archived by us until you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Once you cancel your subscription to the newsletter, the data shall be deleted. This shall not affect data we have been archiving for other purposes. CleverReach This website uses CleverReach for the sending of newsletters. The provider is the CleverReach GmbH & Co. KG, Mühlenstr. 43, 26180 Rastede, Germany. CleverReach is a service that can be used to organize and analyse the sending of newsletters. The data you have entered for the purpose of subscribing to our newsletter (e.g. e-mail address) are stored on servers of CleverReach in Germany or in Ireland.
Newsletters we send out via CleverReach allow us to analyse the user patterns of our newsletter recipients. Among other things, in conjunction with this, it is possible how many recipients actually opened the newsletter e-mail and how often which link inside the newsletter has been clicked. With the assistance of a tool called Conversion Tracking, we can also determine whether an action that has been predefined in the newsletter actually occurred after the link was clicked (e.g. purchase of a product on our website). For more information on the data analysis services by CleverReach newsletters, please go to:
https://www.cleverreach.com/en/features/reporting-tracking/.
The data is processed based on your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR).  You may revoke any consent you have given at any time by unsubscribing from the newsletter. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data processing transactions that have taken place prior to your revocation.
If you do not want to permit an analysis by CleverReach, you must unsubscribe from the newsletter. We provide a link for you to do this in every newsletter message. Moreover, you can also unsubscribe from the newsletter right on the website.
The data you archive with us for the purpose of the newsletter subscription shall be archived by us until you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Once you cancel your subscription to the newsletter, the data shall be deleted from our servers as well as those of CleverReach. This shall not affect data we have been archiving for other purposes.
For more details, please consult the Data Protection Provisions of CleverReach at:
https://www.cleverreach.com/en/privacy-policy/.
Execution of a contract data processing agreement
We have entered into a contract data processing agreement with CleverReach and implement the strict provisions of the German data protection agencies to the fullest when using CleverReach.
YouTube with expanded data protection integration Our website uses plug-ins of the YouTube platform, which is being operated by Google Ireland Limited („Google“), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.
We use YouTube in the expanded data protection mode. According to YouTube, this mode ensures that YouTube does not store any information about visitors to this website before they watch the video. Nevertheless, this does not necessarily mean that the sharing of data with YouTube partners can be ruled out as a result of the expanded data protection mode. For instance, regardless of whether you are watching a video, YouTube will always establish a connection with the Google DoubleClick network.
As soon as you start to play a YouTube video on our website, a connection to YouTube’s servers will be established. As a result, the YouTube server will be notified, which of our pages you have visited. If you are logged into your YouTube account while you visit our site, you enable YouTube to directly allocate your browsing patterns to your personal profile. You have the option to prevent this by logging out of your YouTube account.
Furthermore, after you have started to play a video, YouTube will be able to place various cookies on your device. With the assistance of these cookies, YouTube will be able to obtain information about our website visitor. Among other things, this information will be used to generate video statistics with the aim of improving the user friendliness of the site and to prevent attempts to commit fraud. These cookies will stay on your device until you delete them.
Under certain circumstances, additional data processing transactions may be triggered after you have started to play a YouTube video, which are beyond our control.
The use of YouTube is based on our interest in presenting our online content in an appealing manner. Pursuant to Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR, this is a legitimate interest. By playing the Youtube video you also provide your consent in accordance with Art. 49 Para. 1 P. 1 lit. a GDPR for your data to be processed by the corresponding services in the USA. The USA is considered by the European Court of Justice to be a country with a level of data protection that is inadequate by EU standards. In particular, there is a risk that your data may be processed by US authorities for control and monitoring purposes, possibly without any possibility of legal recourse. If you don't play the Youtube video the transfer described above will not take place.
For more information on how YouTube handles user data, please consult the YouTube Data Privacy Policy under:
https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en.   Google Maps Via an API, this website uses the mapping service Google Maps. The provider is Google Ireland Limited („Google“), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.
To enable the use of the Google Maps features, your IP address must be stored. As a rule, this information is transferred to one of Google’s servers in the United States, where it is archived. The operator of this website has no control over the data transfer.
We use Google Maps to present our online content in an appealing manner and to make the locations disclosed on our website easy to find. This constitutes a legitimate interest as defined in Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. By clicking Google Maps you also provide your consent in accordance with Art. 49 Para. 1 P. 1 lit. a GDPR for your data to be processed by the corresponding services in the USA. The USA is considered by the European Court of Justice to be a country with a level of data protection that is inadequate by EU standards. In particular, there is a risk that your data may be processed by US authorities for control and monitoring purposes, possibly without any possibility of legal recourse. If you don't click Google Maps the transfer described above will not take place.
For more information on the handling of user data, please review Google’s Data Privacy Declaration under:
https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en. Use of SalesViewer® technology This website uses SalesViewer® technology from SalesViewer® GmbH on the basis of the website operator’s legitimate interests (Section 6 paragraph 1 lit.f GDPR) in order to collect and save data on marketing, market research and optimisation purposes. In order to do this, a javascript based code, which serves to capture company-related data and according website usage. The data captured using this technology are encrypted in a non-retrievable one-way function (so-called hashing). The data is immediately pseudonymised and is not used to identify website visitors personally.
The data recording and storage can be repealed at any time with immediate effect for the future, by clicking on www.salesviewer.com/opt-out in order to prevent SalesViewer® from recording your data. In this case, an opt-out cookie for this website is saved on your device. If you delete the cookies in the browser, you will need to click on this link again.
Job Applications We offer website visitors the opportunity to submit job applications to us (e.g. via e-mail, via postal services on by submitting the online job application form). Below, we will brief you on the scope, purpose and use of the personal data collected from you in conjunction with the application process. We assure you that the collection, processing and use of your data will occur in compliance with the applicable data privacy rights and all other statutory provisions and that your data will always be treated as strictly confidential.
Scope and purpose of the collection of data
If you submit a job application to us, we will process any affiliated personal data (e.g. contact and communications data, application documents, notes taken during job interviews, etc.), if they are required to make a decision concerning the establishment or an employment relationship. The legal grounds for the aforementioned are § 26 New GDPR according to German Law (Negotiation of an Employment Relationship), Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR (General Contract Negotiations) and – provided you have given us your consent – Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR. You may revoke any consent given at any time. Within our company, your personal data will only be shared with individuals who are involved in the processing of your job application.
If your job application should result in your recruitment, the data you have submitted will be archived on the grounds of § 26 New GDPR and Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR for the purpose of implementing the employment relationship in our data processing system.
Data Archiving Period
If we should not be able to offer you a position, if you refuse a job offer, retract your application, revoke your consent to the processing of your data or ask us to delete your data, we will store your transferred data, incl. any physically submitted application documents for a maximum of 6 months after the conclusion of the application process (retention period) to enable us to track the details of the application process in the event of disparities (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR).
YOU HAVE THE OPTION TO OBJECT TO THIS STORAGE/RETENTION OF YOUR DATA IF YOU HAVE LEGITIMATE INTERESTS TO DO SO THAT OUTWEIGH OUR INTERESTS.
Once the retention period has expired, the data will be deleted, unless we are subject to any other statutory retention obligations or if any other legal grounds exist to continue to store the data. If it should be foreseeable that the retention of your data will be necessary after the retention period has expired (e.g. due to imminent or pending litigation), the data shall not be deleted until the data have become irrelevant. This shall be without prejudice to any other statutory retention periods. Our social media appearances Data processing through social networks We maintain publicly available profiles in social networks. The individual social networks we use can be found below.
Social networks such as Facebook, LinkedIn etc. can generally analyse your user behaviour comprehensively if you visit their website or a website with integrated social media content (e.g. like buttons or banner ads). When you visit our social media pages, numerous data protection-relevant processing operations are triggered. In detail:
If you are logged in to your social media account and visit our social media page, the operator of the social media portal can assign this visit to your user account. Under certain circumstances, your personal data may also be recorded if you are not logged in or do not have an account with the respective social media portal. In this case, this data is collected, for example, via cookies stored on your device or by recording your IP address.
Using the data collected in this way, the operators of the social media portals can create user profiles in which their preferences and interests are stored. This way you can see interest-based advertising inside and outside of your social media presence. If you have an account with the social network, interest-based advertising can be displayed on any device you are logged in to or have logged in to.
Please also note that we cannot retrace all processing operations on the social media portals. Depending on the provider, additional processing operations may therefore be carried out by the operators of the social media portals. Details can be found in the terms of use and privacy policy of the respective social media portals.
Legal basis
Our social media appearances should ensure the widest possible presence on the Internet. This is a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. The analysis processes initiated by the social networks may be based on divergent legal bases to be specified by the operators of the social networks (e.g. consent within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) (a) GDPR). For this purpose, this website may use a service in the USA, e.g. Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Pinterest and many more. By clicking "Confirm selection" or "Select & confirm all", you also provide your consent in accordance with Art. 49 Para. 1 P. 1 lit. a GDPR for your data to be processed by the corresponding services in the USA. The USA is considered by the European Court of Justice to be a country with a level of data protection that is inadequate by EU standards. In particular, there is a risk that your data may be processed by US authorities for control and monitoring purposes, possibly without any possibility of legal recourse. If you click "Accept only required cookies", the transfer described above will not take place.
Responsibility and assertion of rights
If you visit one of our social media sites (e.g., Facebook), we, together with the operator of the social media platform, are responsible for the data processing operations triggered during this visit. You can in principle protect your rights (information, correction, deletion, limitation of processing, data portability and complaint) vis-à-vis us as well as vis-à-vis the operator of the respective social media portal (e.g. Facebook).
Please note that despite the shared responsibility with the social media portal operators, we do not have full influence on the data processing operations of the social media portals. Our options are determined by the company policy of the respective provider.
Storage time
The data collected directly from us via the social media presence will be deleted from our systems as soon as the purpose for their storage lapses, you ask us to delete it, you revoke your consent to the storage or the purpose for the data storage lapses. Stored cookies remain on your device until you delete them. Mandatory statutory provisions - in particular, retention periods - remain unaffected.
We have no control over the storage duration of your data that are stored by the social network operators for their own purposes. For details, please contact the social network operators directly (e.g. in their privacy policy, see below).
Individual social networks Facebook
We have a profile on Facebook. The provider is Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA.
You can customise your advertising settings independently in your user account. Click on the following link and log in:
https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads.
Details can be found in the Facebook privacy policy:
https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/. Twitter
We use the short message service Twitter. The provider is Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, United States.
You can customise your Twitter privacy settings in your user account.
Click on the following link and log in:
https://twitter.com/personalization.
For details, see the Twitter Privacy Policy:
https://twitter.com/privacy. Instagram
We have a profile on Instagram. The provider is Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA. For details on how they handle your personal information, see the Instagram Privacy Policy:
https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875. Pinterest
We have a profile at Pinterest. The operator is Pinterest Inc., 808 Brannan Street, San Francisco, CA 94103-490, USA („Pinterest“). Details on how they handle your personal data can be found in the privacy policy of Pinterest:
https://policy.pinterest.com/de/privacy-policy. XING
We have a profile on XING. The provider is XING AG, Dammtorstraße 29-32, 20354 Hamburg, Germany. Details on their handling of your personal data can be found in the XING Privacy Policy:
https://privacy.xing.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung. LinkedIn
We have a LinkedIn profile. The provider is the LinkedIn Ireland Unlimited Company, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland. LinkedIn uses advertising cookies.
If you want to disable LinkedIn advertising cookies, please use the following link:
https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls/retargeting-opt-out.
For details on how they handle your personal information, please refer to LinkedIn's privacy policy:
https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy.
Always there for you
– Change location: Change locationEgyptSyriaAlgeriaChinaSouth KoreaJapanThailandTaiwanIndiaHong Kong SAR of ChinaSingaporeMalaysiaUnited Arab EmiratesVietnamOmanBahrainBangladeshGermanyFranceItalySpainUnited KingdomSwitzerlandNetherlandsTurkeyUnited StatesMexicoBrazilAll Others …
Write an email:
Phone:
Linkedin
Instagram
Youtube
Twitter
Facebook
Xing
Fischer – worldwideChange locationChange locationEgyptSyriaAlgeriaChinaSouth KoreaJapanThailandTaiwanIndiaHong Kong SAR of ChinaSingaporeMalaysiaUnited Arab EmiratesVietnamOmanBahrainBangladeshGermanyFranceItalySpainUnited KingdomSwitzerlandNetherlandsTurkeyUnited StatesMexicoBrazilAll Others …/ Contact directly:Phone:Phone:Contact form Online shopServiceContactShow help menu Jump to the top of the page
